先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひかり）ハア ハア… 先生！
Mr. T!
（高橋(たかはし)）ん？　どうした？
What's up?
I just saw someone suspicious!
不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
（ひかり）
不審者… 不審者を見た！
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.)
なに？
ど… どんなヤツだった？
What? Wh-What did they look like?
Um, he was really big, like a bear,
熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great
ええと… 熊みたいに大きくて
（高橋）うんうん
with really shaggy hair!
毛[け]:hair|fur|down, 毛[もう]:one-thousandth/0.03 mm (one-thousandth of a sun)|old monetary unit (0.0001 yen), もじゃもじゃ:tousled/shaggy (hair)/scraggly (beard), っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out
毛が こう
もじゃもじゃっぽかった
もじゃもじゃ:tousled/shaggy (hair)/scraggly (beard)
（高橋）もじゃもじゃ
Shaggy?
And he had eyes like a beast, targeting its prey!
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at, 獣[けもの, けだもの]:beast/brute/animal, 獣[しし]:beast (esp. one used for its meat, such as a boar or a deer)|hunting (of animals such as boar, deer, etc.), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
それで
目は獲物を狙う獣みたいだった
That can't be anything but a bear!
完全[かんぜん]:perfection/completeness, 熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae)
完全に熊なんだが！
♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
（早紀絵(さきえ)）ん？
（クルツ）うっ うう… くっ
Someone is sitting in the hallway crying.
廊下[ろうか]:corridor/hallway/passageway, 膝[ひざ, ヒザ]:knee|lap/knee and thigh (while sitting), 抱える[かかえる]:to hold or carry under or in the arms|to have (esp. problems, debts, etc.)|to employ, ぐずる:to grumble/to be unsettled/to grizzle
（早紀絵）
廊下で膝を抱えて
ぐずってる子がいる
That looks like a school uniform, but not this school's...
制服[せいふく]:uniform, 学校[がっこう]:school
制服のようだけど
うちの学校のものとは違うかな
And such nice blond hair.
きれい:pretty/lovely|clean, ブロンド:blonde
それにしても きれいなブロンド
（早紀絵）
どうしたの？　大丈夫？
What's wrong? Are you okay?
What a pretty boy!
美男子[びだんし, びなんし]:handsome man
（早紀絵）
美男子！
Ms. Succubus Is Inquisitive
I'm Satou Sakie, the math teacher.
数学[すうがく]:mathematics/arithmetic, 教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom)
（早紀絵）
私 数学教師の
佐藤(さとう)早紀絵っていいます
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
よろしくね
Nice to meet you.
Ms. Sakie...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（クルツ）早紀絵先生
My name is Kurtz.
僕はクルツっていいます
Are you part German, by any chance?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, ドイツ:Germany, 系[けい]:system|corollary|system (range of strata that correspond to a particular time period)|, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
もしかしてクルツ君って
ドイツ系かしら？
Yes, I am.
ご存じ[ごぞんじ]:knowing|(an) acquaintance
（クルツ）
はい そうです
よくご存じですね
I'm surprised you could tell.
A lucky guess.
たまたま:casually/unexpectedly/accidentally
（早紀絵）たまたまよ
I happen to have studied a bit of German in college.
たまたま:casually/unexpectedly/accidentally, ドイツ語[ドイツご]:German (language), 履修[りしゅう]:taking a class/studying a subject/completing a course
たまたま大学でドイツ語履修してて
それで…
So...
So what are you doing here, Kurtz?
所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
それで クルツ君は
こんな所で何を？
あっ ああ その…
Well, I came here with someone, but we got separated.
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, はぐれる:to lose sight of (one's companions)/to stray from|to miss (one's chance to ...), しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
一緒に来た人がいたんですが
その人と はぐれてしまって
Was it your parents?
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.), 御[ご]:honorific/polite|honorific suffix, 御[ぎょ]:honorific affix|honorific prefix, 転入[てんにゅう]:move in (to a new house), 手続き[てつづき]:procedure/(legal) process/formalities, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
（早紀絵）
一緒に来た人って親御さん？
転入の手続きとかかしら？
Were they filling out transfer paperwork?
Y-Yes...
えっ ええ… そうです
That's right.
Doesn't look like it.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（早紀絵）
違うみたい
（クルツ）うう…
It looks he isn't really a transfer student,
転入生[てんにゅうせい]:transfer student, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（早紀絵）
転入生っていうのは
ウソみたいだけど
but he doesn't seem like a bad kid.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
でも 悪い子には見えないし…
Oh, Ms. Satou...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（雪(ゆき)）あっ 佐藤先生
Hello!
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
こんにちは
Hello.
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
（町(まち)）こんにちは
Hello.
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
（早紀絵）こんにちは
（クルツ）ほ〜
That girl's head was...
女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 首[くび, クビ]:neck|head|dismissal, 首[しゅきゅう, しるし]:decapitated head of an enemy
あの女の子 首が…
Yes, she's a demi-human. A dullahan.
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person)
そうね　あの子は亜人(あじん)
デュラハンだから
Really? She is?
そうですか あの子が…
Oh? Are you interested in demi-humans, Kurtz?
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for), かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
あら クルツ君は
亜人に興味があるのかしら？
No, not especially.
いえ 別に
He totally is.
（早紀絵）
あるのね…
Guess I should ask why he's really here.
やはり:too/also|still, ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions
やはり
ちゃんと事情を聞いたほうが…
But will he actually tell me the truth?
果たして[はたして]:as was expected/just as one thought|really? (in questions), 素直[すなお]:obedient/meek|honest, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
でも 果たして
素直に話してくれるかどうか…
I should use my aphrodisiac effect to make him talk—
いっそ:rather/sooner/preferably, 無理やり[むりやり]:forcibly/against one's will, しゃべる:to talk/to chat/to chatter
いっそ催淫(さいいん)して
無理やりしゃべらせ…
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
ないない:family circle/the inside/private
ないない ないない！
Why am I suddenly thinking like that? Jeez!
唐突[とうとつ]:abrupt/sudden, 考え[かんがえ]:thinking|idea|intention||
なんで唐突に
こんなこと考え… もう！
Um, where are you going?
どちら:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives)
あの… どちらへ？
I'll go and look for your parents.
親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.), 御[ご]:honorific/polite|honorific suffix, 御[ぎょ]:honorific affix|honorific prefix
あなたの親御さんを
捜しに行きましょう
That will probably be faster.
多分[たぶん]:perhaps/probably|generous, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
多分 それが手っとり早いから
ささっ
Off, I go!
Hey, wait—
あっ ちょっ まっ…
（手をつかむ音）
あっ ああ…
Oh, no—
しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
（早紀絵）
しまった…
ん？
The effect isn't working?
（早紀絵）
催淫されない？
That does sometimes happen with people who haven't much sexual desire.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 極端[きょくたん]:extreme/extremity, 性欲[せいよく]:sexual desire, 薄い[うすい]:thin|pale|watery||, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
確かに極端に性欲の薄い人は
そういうこともあるかもしれない
But he doesn't look that way.
感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
でも そういう感じには見えない
Maybe he's actually more...
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||
この子 私が思ってる以上に…
Ms. Satou!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（高橋）佐藤先生
（２人）ん？
Mr. Takahashi?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（早紀絵）
高橋先生
どうかされたんですか？
Is something wrong?
Yes. Hikari told me she saw someone suspicious in the school.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 校内[こうない]:within a school, 不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
ええ　実は
ひかりが校内で不審者を見たと
Huh? Someone suspicious?
不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
（早紀絵）ふ… 不審者ですか？
（クルツ）え？
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray
見たのが ひかりなんで
Hikari saw them,
いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), 証言[しょうげん]:testimony/(verbal) evidence, 盛る[さかる]:to prosper/to flourish|to copulate (animals), 盛る[もる]:to serve (food, etc.)|to fill up|to prescribe||, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
いろいろ証言を
盛っているかもしれませんが
so she may have exaggerated some of the details,
but I wanted to warn you.
一応[いちおう]:more or less|tentatively|just in case|, 注意[ちゅうい]:caution/being careful/attention (heed)
一応 注意を
Suspicious... Could it have been...
不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
不審者 もしや…
Ms. Sakie has such a serious look on her face.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 深刻[しんこく]:serious/severe/grave, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
（クルツ）
早紀絵先生
あんなに深刻な顔をして
She must be scared of the suspicious person.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
やっぱり
不審者が怖いんだろうな
She doesn't seem to fully trust me, either.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 疑う[うたがう]:to doubt/to distrust/to be suspicious of, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
早紀絵先生は
なにか僕を疑ってるみたいだし
If I want to allay her suspicion of me...
疑惑[ぎわく]:doubt/misgivings/distrust, 目をそらす[めをそらす]:to look away/to avert one's eyes
疑惑の目をそらすためにも…
No, to thank her for her kindness to me...
優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
いや 優しくしてくれた
早紀絵先生に
恩返しをする[おんがえしをする]:to return a favor (favour)/to repay
恩返しをするために
不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
不審者は
僕が なんとかします！
I'll do something about the suspicious person!
誰？
Who's this?
Let's go!
Well... His name is Kurtz.
えっと:let me see/well/errr ...
えっとですね
彼 クルツ君といって
I'll take that suspicious person, and give 'em this and this!
He was separated from the people he came here with.
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, はぐれる:to lose sight of (one's companions)/to stray from|to miss (one's chance to ...), しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
一緒に来た人と
はぐれてしまったそうなんです
You just wait, suspicious person!
I wonder if the suspicious person she mentioned was one of them.
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
もしかしたら 不審者っていうのは
その人なんじゃないかって
I see.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, ちなみ:association/link|pledge (esp. for marriage), 不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
（高橋）
なるほど
ちなみに不審者は
Actually, she said the person was a huge man, who looked like a bear.
熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 大男[おおおとこ]:great man/giant
熊みたいな大男だったと
言ってました
Someone like you, I wonder.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
（早紀絵）
高橋先生みたいな感じですかね？
Huh?
（高橋）え？
（クルツ）はっ
Nah, I'm sure he was much bigger than—
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 大きな[おおきな]:big/large/great
（高橋）
いやあ
きっと 私なんかよりも大きな…
下がる[さがる]:to come down|to hang|to move back||
下がって！
Get back!
（クルツ）ふっ
（宇垣(うがき)）うおっ
（クルツ）たあ〜！
（宇垣）うっ うおっ
（宇垣）うわっ いって〜！
Ouch!
いてる:to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal
（２人）うわ〜！
（宇垣）いててて…
Ow, ow, ow!
Are you all right, Ms. Sakie?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（クルツ）
おケガはありませんか？
早紀絵先生
Y-Yes, that was amazing, Kurtz.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
（早紀絵）
え… ええ
すごいのね クルツ君　ん？
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow...
いてる:to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal
（宇垣）いててて…
Ugaki?
宇垣さん？
え… あっ あの…
U-Uh...
Hey, Kurtz... I thought you'd disappeared.
（宇垣）よお クルツ
突然[とつぜん]:abrupt/sudden/unexpected, 急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||
突然 いなくなったと思ったら
どうした 急に？　え？
What brings you here now? Huh?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
げっ 先輩！
Mr. Ugaki?
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 後輩[こうはい]:junior (at work, school, etc.)/younger people/younger student
（高橋）先輩？
（早紀絵）後輩なんですか？
He works under you?
He's speaking with respect?
（高橋）え？
（早紀絵）あ…
Oh, um... He's a police detective I know.
えっと:let me see/well/errr ..., 知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance, 刑事[けいじ]:(police) detective|criminal matter
その… えっと…
知り合いの刑事さんです
刑事[けいじ]:(police) detective|criminal matter
刑事？
A police detective?
Jeez, what if you'd been wrong?
ったく:good grief (expression of exasperation), 外れる[はずれる]:to be disconnected/to get out of place/to be off
ったく 外れたらどうすんだ？
I'm sorry.
すみませんでした
知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
お知り合いなんですね
You know each other?
Yes, for quite some time, you might say...
古く[ふるく]:anciently/formerly
ええ 古くからの
といいますか…
（高橋）ん？
で この子…
あっ いえ クルツ君は？
And this boy— I mean, Kurtz...
部下[ぶか]:subordinate person
（宇垣）まあ 俺の部下だ
Oh, he works for me.
ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter)
そうなんです ハハハ…
That's right.
Why are you at the school, Ugaki?
学校[がっこう]:school
宇垣さん どうして学校に？
（宇垣）ん？　まあ…
（高橋）あっ
Well, I guess you could say...
（宇垣）なんつうか…
Um, did you check in?
受付[うけつけ]:reception (desk)/information desk|receipt
あの 受付には？
（宇垣）受付？
Check in?
To enter the school, the rule is that you have to register your name.
校内[こうない]:within a school, 受付[うけつけ]:reception (desk)/information desk|receipt, 名簿[めいぼ]:register of names/list of names/roll, 名簿[みょうぶ]:proof of identity (for nobles, doctors, etc.) (Heian period)
校内に入るには
受付で名簿に
記帳[きちょう]:registry/entry/book-keeping, いただく:to receive/to get|to eat, 決まり[きまり]:rule|settlement|habit||
名前を記帳していただく
決まりなんですが…
Oh, sorry about that.
ああ それは すまんかった
じゃあ クルツ お前行ってこい
Okay, Kurtz, you go do that.
Huh?
ええ…
露骨[ろこつ]:frank|conspicuous|broad, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
（宇垣）露骨に嫌な顔すんな
Don't look so annoyed!
刑事[けいじ]:(police) detective|criminal matter, 随分[ずいぶん]:very/extremely|contemptible, 若い[わかい]:young|immature|low (number), 海外[かいがい]:foreign/abroad/overseas, っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out
刑事にしては随分若いし
海外の人っぽいですね
He seems young for a police detective, and he looks foreign.
そうですね
That's true.
Guess the police force is pretty broad-minded...
警察[けいさつ]:police|police officer|police station, 懐[ふところ]:bosom/bust|(breast) pocket, 深い[ふかい]:deep|profound|dense||
警察は懐が深いんだな
If you'll buy me takoyaki on the way home, I'll do it.
帰り[かえり]:return/coming back, たこ焼き[たこやき, タコやき]:octopus dumplings, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
帰りに たこ焼きを
買ってくれるなら行きます
てめえ:you (used by young males)|oneself
うっ てめえ…
You little...
懐[ふところ]:bosom/bust|(breast) pocket, 深い[ふかい]:deep|profound|dense||
（高橋）懐 深いな〜
So broad-minded.
（早紀絵）そうですね
Indeed.
（早紀絵）んっ
（宇垣）うん？
校内[こうない]:within a school, 土足[どそく]:shod feet|muddy feet/dirty feet, 厳禁[げんきん]:strict prohibition/ban/interdiction
校内は土足厳禁です
No outside shoes allowed in the school.
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, スリッパ:slipper/slippers, 履く[はく]:to put on (or wear) lower-body clothing (i.e. pants, skirt, etc.)|to affix a sword to one's hip|to affix a bowstring to a bow, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
ちゃんと スリッパ履いてください
Put on the slippers.
Oh, sorry about that.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
（宇垣）ああ いやあ 悪(わり)い 悪い
高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, しばらく:little while/short while|a while
高校に来るなんて
しばらくぶりだったからよ
It's been a while since I've been in a high school.
Why are you here?
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
一体 どうしたんですか？
（宇垣）ん？
We usually meet at a coffee shop.
喫茶店[きっさてん, きっちゃてん]:coffee shop/tearoom/coffee lounge
いつもは喫茶店とかで
会ってるじゃないですか
Yeah, well...
まあな
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school
同じ高校に
When I heard that there were four demis at the same school,
集まる[あつまる]:to gather/to collect/to assemble, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
デミが４人も集まっちまった
なんて聞いたら
I thought I should at least see them, given my line of work.
職業柄[しょくぎょうがら]:due to the nature of one's job/because of one's line of work, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
職業柄 顔くらい見ときたいからな
Also, uh...
それに ああ…
Kurtz?
（早紀絵）クルツ君ですか？
ほほう:horse gait|way of walking (e.g. in martial arts, etc.), ほほう:revitalizing treatment that stimulates the organs or the meridians (in Chinese medicine)
ああ… ほほう
あいつと何かあったのか？
Oh? Did something happen between you and him?
Hmm? Hmm?
ん？　ん〜？
うっ まあ… まあ…
Well... Sort of...
フフフフッ
Just the fact that you and he touched makes my coming here worthwhile.
接触[せっしょく]:touch/contact, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however
お前とクルツが
接触したってだけでも
来たかいが あったってもんだ
なあ ええ？
Right?
You're infuriating!
腹立つ[はらだつ]:to get angry
腹立つ
I can't give too many details, but...
詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
今はまだ
詳しいことは言えないがな
Put your name and address here.
住所[じゅうしょ]:address (e.g. of house)/residence/domicile
（高橋）ここに名前と住所を
Okay.
（クルツ）あっ はい
So, what kind of work do you do?
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
それで クルツ君は
どんな仕事を？
Gulp...
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
ぎくっ！
あっ 亜人関係とかじゃないです
I-It has nothing to do with demi-humans!
Really, it has nothing to do with demi-humans at all!
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
いや もう
亜人とか全然関係ないですから
Not demi-humans!
さしずめ:after all/when all's said and done|for the time being, 対[たい]:opposite|versus|to (e.g. "winning a game five to three")||, 対[つい]:pair|antithesis|counter for items that come in pairs|, 用[よう]:business|use|for the use of ...|, 決戦[けっせん]:decisive battle/deciding match/play-off, 兵器[へいき]:arms/weapons/ordnance
（宇垣）
クルツは さしずめ
対サキュバス用の決戦兵器
Basically, Kurtz is our weapon against succubi.
Something like that.
そんなところだ フフッ
Stop trying to make this sound like some anime.
アニメ:animated film/animated cartoon/anime (when referring to Japanese cartoons), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 言い回し[いいまわし]:expression/phraseology, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
そういうアニメみたいな言い回し
やめてください
Sorry.
すいません
So, how have things been lately?
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now
で どうだ 最近は？
元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy
元気にしてたか？
You doing well?
How have things been?
どおり:in accordance with/following|roughly, ぼちぼち:little-by-little/gradually|not bad
どうって いつもどおりですよ
ぼちぼちです
Just like always. I'm getting by.
Honestly, I think you're doing great.
正直[しょうじき]:honesty/integrity|honestly, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
正直
お前はうまくやってると思うよ
Given the depth of their natures,
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 濃い[こい]:deep (colour)|strong (flavour, smell, etc.)|thick (consistency)||
性質の濃いサキュバスは
succubi generally either live apart from society
大抵[たいてい]:mostly|probably|most||, 世間[せけん]:world/society, 離れる[はなれる]:to be separated|to leave|to leave (a job, etc.)|, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 引きこもる[ひきこもる]:to stay indoors/to be confined indoors
大抵 世間から離れて
一人で引きこもっちまうか
or just throw caution to the wind and live boldly.
逆[ぎゃく]:reverse|converse (of a hypothesis, etc.)|inverse (function), 逆[さか]:inverse/reverse, 気味[きみ, きび]:sensation/feeling|tendency, 気味[ぎみ]:-like/-looking/-looked, 大胆[だいたん]:bold/daring/audacious
逆に やけ気味に
大胆になっちまうかの
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives)
どっちかだからな
警察[けいさつ]:police|police officer|police station, 世話になる[せわになる]:to receive favor (favour)/to be much obliged to someone/to be indebted
まっ 警察の世話になるのは
Usually, we police deal with the troublemakers in the latter category.
後者[こうしゃ]:the latter, 大胆[だいたん]:bold/daring/audacious, 困る[こまる]:to be troubled/to be worried/to be bothered
後者の
大胆な困ったちゃんなわけだが
Among succubi, upright members of society like you are rare.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, しっかり:tightly (holding on)/firmly|strongly (built), 社会人[しゃかいじん]:working adult/full-fledged member of society
お前みたいに
しっかり社会人やってけるヤツは
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 珍しい[めずらしい]:unusual|new|fine (e.g. gift)
ホントに珍しいんだ
Of course, the government is facing the tough situation succubi are currently in—
まあ サキュバスにとって
まだまだ:still some way to go before the goal/still more to come/much more, 酷[こく]:severe/harsh/stringent, 現状[げんじょう]:present condition/existing state/status quo, 国[くに]:country|region|national government||, 課題[かだい]:subject|homework|task, でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
まだまだ酷な現状は
国の課題でもあって…
Smoke in the smoking room!
たばこ:tobacco/cigarette|tobacco plant (Nicotiana tabacum), 喫煙所[きつえんしょ, きつえんじょ]:smoking area (corner)
たばこは喫煙所
意志[いし]:will/volition/intention, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
ああ お前が意志を持って
I fully realize you consciously live as a functional adult.
社会人[しゃかいじん]:working adult/full-fledged member of society, 百[ひゃく, もも]:100/hundred, 承知[しょうち]:knowledge|consent|forgiving
社会人やってるのは
百も承知だけどよ
But isn't it about time you thought about settling down and starting a family?
そろそろ:slowly/quietly|soon, 身を固める[みをかためる]:to settle down/to get a steady job|to attire oneself
そろそろ身を固めて
家庭[かてい]:home/family/household, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
家庭に入ることを
考えてもいいんじゃないか？
I can introduce you to some guys.
紹介[しょうかい]:introduction/presentation/referral
男なら紹介するぞ
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||
どうしたんですか？　急に
Where's this coming from?
Nowhere special.
（宇垣）
別に〜
おっさんってのは
It just makes me worry to see a young woman living all alone.
年頃[としごろ]:approximate age|marriageable age (esp. of a woman)|appropriate age (to ...)|, 女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 独り身[ひとりみ]:unmarried man (woman), 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
年頃の女の子が独り身だと
心配しちゃうの
Especially you, having known you since you were little.
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, 小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny
特に お前のことは
小さいころから知ってるからよ
You sound like a father, Ugaki.
お父さん[おとうさん, おとっさん]:father/dad/papa, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
宇垣さんって
お父さんみたいですね
Who are you calling a father?
親父[おやじ, ろうや]:one's father/old man/one's boss
（宇垣）誰が親父(おやじ)だと？　こらっ
父親[ちちおや]:father, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
（早紀絵）
でも 本当の父親より
父親らしいことしてくれます
But you do more fatherly things for me than my actual father.
You aren't supposed to say that.
（宇垣）
そういうことは言うもんじゃない
I'm sorry.
（早紀絵）すみません
Marriage, huh?
結婚[けっこん]:marriage
結婚ですか
Actually, there is someone I'm interested in.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
実は 私
今 気になってる人がいて…
えっ マジ？
Seriously?!
What's with that reaction?
リアクション:reaction, 話題[わだい]:topic/subject, 振る[ふる]:to wave|to sprinkle|to cast (actor)||, 振る[ぶる]:assuming the air of .../behaving like ...|to put on airs
何ですか そのリアクション
自分で話題 振っておいて
You're the one who brought it up.
Uh, yeah, sorry.
（宇垣）ああ いや すまん
話題になる[わだいになる]:to be in the news/to be talked about/to become a popular topic of conversation, 言い訳[いいわけ]:excuse|explanation, ばっか:only/merely|approximately
だって この手の話題になると
お前いつも言い訳ばっかするだろ？
But you always make excuses when this subject comes up.
Like you don't want to use your aphrodisiac effect to get a boyfriend,
恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, 恋[こい]:(romantic) love
催淫して恋人を作りたくないとか
本物の恋が分からないとか
or you don't know what real love is.
I never thought you'd find a man yourself!
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 見つける[みつける, みっける]:to discover|to locate|to be used to seeing
まさか 自分で男を見つけるとは
触る[さわる]:to touch/to feel
触りますよ
Don't make me touch you.
Hey, don't!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（宇垣）やめろ
Getting too worked up is hard on a man my age!
年齢[ねんれい]:age/years, ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat, 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 苦労[くろう]:troubles/hardships
この年齢になると
ドキドキすんのも 一苦労なの
情けない[なさけない, なっさけない]:miserable/pitiable/shameful
（早紀絵）ふん！　情けない
Hmph. Pathetic.
The man I'm interested in doesn't have much sexual desire.
気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy, 性欲[せいよく]:sexual desire, 薄い[うすい]:thin|pale|watery||
私の気になる人は性欲が薄くて
触れる[ふれる]:to touch|to experience|to touch on a subject||
私が触れても催淫されないのに
My touch doesn't even affect him.
え？
そんなことあるわけねえだろうが
Huh?
There's no way that's possible.
え？
Other than gays,
かぎり:limit/limits|degree
ゲイでもないかぎり
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
お前に催淫されない男なんて
いねえよ？
there's no man your aphrodisiac effect wouldn't work on.
But he... He didn't seem affected at all...
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
でも その人は
催淫されていたようには全然…
That just means he didn't look affected.
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
（宇垣）
見えなかったってだけだろ？
I bet he knows a lot about demis, right?
そいつ:he/she|that, 詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well
そいつ
デミに詳しいんじゃないか？
Y-Yes...
えっ ええ…
Even if your aphrodisiac effect did work on him,
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, そいつ:he/she|that, 万が一[まんがいち, まんがいつ]:if by any chance/just in case/in the worst case, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
きっと そいつは
万が一 催淫されることがあっても
he was probably making an effort not to show it.
表[おもて]:surface|face (i.e. the visible side of an object)|front (of a building, etc.)||, 表[ひょう]:table (e.g. Table 1)/chart/list, 気をつける[きをつける]:to be careful/to pay attention/to take care
表には出すまいと
気をつけていたんだろうよ
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
見えなかっただけ…
He didn't look affected,
してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
催淫はしていた
but he actually was?
He actually was?
してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
催淫していた
Yes! Your aphrodisiac effect did its job on him!
そうだ！
その男はお前に催淫されていたのだ
He isn't special!
特別[とくべつ]:special
特別ではないのだ
Are you disappointed?
失望[しつぼう]:disappointment/despair
失望したか？
Are your feelings for him real?
対する[たいする]:to face (each other)|to be directed toward (the future, etc.)|to receive (a client, etc.)||, 好意[こうい]:good will/favor/favour, 本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal
その男に対する
お前の好意は本物か？
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
まだ 好きだと
言えるのか？
Can you still say you like him?
When that happened, Mr. Takahashi
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（早紀絵）
あのとき
高橋先生は催淫されていた？
was affected by my aphrodisiac effect?
He was excited by me?!
ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
私に ドキドキしていた？
あっ ああ…
ハッ そうか そうか
I see, I see.
If you can believe that it's okay to use your aphrodisiac effect,
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 思える[おもえる]:to seem/to appear likely
お前が催淫しても
悪くないと思えるなら
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
そりゃ もう
ホントに好きってことなんだろうよ
that would mean you truly love him.
W-Would it really?
（早紀絵）そっ そうですかね
（宇垣）え？
I only took interest in Taka—
興味を持つ[きょうみをもつ]:to have an interest
（早紀絵）
私が たか…
その人に興味を持ったのは その…
in him to begin with because when I touched his hand,
触れる[ふれる]:to touch|to experience|to touch on a subject||
前に手が触れたとき
there was no indication that he'd felt my aphrodisiac effect.
そぶり:behavior/behaviour/manner, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
その人に催淫されたそぶりが
見えなかったという
前提[ぜんてい]:preamble/premise/reason
前提があったからであって
Learning that it really had affected him did excite me a little,
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat
今 実は催淫されてたと知って
少しドキドキしたけれど
but it contradicts the very reason why I took interest in him...
興味を持つ[きょうみをもつ]:to have an interest, 前提[ぜんてい]:preamble/premise/reason, 矛盾[むじゅん]:contradiction/inconsistency
それは私がその人に
興味を持った前提と矛盾していて
Which means my excitement is transient,
ドキドキ:thump-thump/bang-bang/pit-a-pat, 一過性[いっかせい]:transient (pain or fever), 本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, 難い[かたい]:difficult/hard, 難い[にくい, がたい]:difficult to .../hard to ...
つまり 今のドキドキは
一過性のもので本物とは言い難い
and can't be called the real thing, but...
恋[こい]:(romantic) love, 始まり[はじまり]:origin/beginning
でも “恋の始まりとは—”
I'm pretty sure I read in a romance how-to book that
得てして[えてして]:often (happens), 勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess, 先入観[せんにゅうかん]:preconception/prejudice/preoccupation, 恋愛[れんあい]:love/love-making/passion, ハウツー:how-to, 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||
“得てして勘違いや先入観である”
と恋愛のハウツー本に
the beginning of love is often mistaken or preconceived...
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
確か そんなことが…
勢い[いきおい]:force|influence|impetus|, 任せ[まかせ]:leaving everything up to someone else, 恋愛[れんあい]:love/love-making/passion, 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 教育者[きょういくしゃ]:educator/teacher/educationalist, しめる:to strangle/to constrict, しめる:to be wet/to become wet|to be in low spirits
いや そんな勢い任せの恋愛は
一教育者としてしめ… しめ…
I mean, as an educator, I feel that love carried by momentum is... is...
△＄□％○…
But... But if someone seriously pursued me, I'd...
真剣[しんけん]:seriousness/earnestness|real sword (as opposed to unsharpened or wooden practice weapon), 求める[もとめる]:to want|to request|to seek|, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly
でも でも 真剣に求められたら
きっと そのとき私は…
If a succubus fell under an aphrodisiac effect...
サキュバスが催淫されてら
あっ
うう〜
（宇垣）見てられない
I couldn't bear to watch.
（早紀絵）もう！
Damn it!
Interviews with Monster Girls
Maybe I shouldn't have said that...
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
（クルツ）
さっきのは マズかったかな
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, 気付く[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
亜人関係って
気付かれてないといいけど…
I hope no one's figured out my connection with demi-humans.
Someone suspicious?
不審者[ふしんしゃ]:suspicious person
（雪）不審者？
（ひかり）うん
Yeah.
What was he like?
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.)
（町）どんな人だったの？
ええと:let me see/well/errr ..., 熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great
（ひかり）
ええと 熊みたいに大きくて…
Well, he was huge, like a bear...
熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae)
熊？
A bear?
And he had shaggy hair...
毛[け]:hair|fur|down, 毛[もう]:one-thousandth/0.03 mm (one-thousandth of a sun)|old monetary unit (0.0001 yen), もじゃもじゃ:tousled/shaggy (hair)/scraggly (beard), っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out
毛が こう もじゃもじゃっぽくて
Shaggy?
もじゃもじゃ:tousled/shaggy (hair)/scraggly (beard)
もじゃもじゃ？
And he had eyes like a beast, targeting its prey!
獲物[えもの]:game/spoils/trophy, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at, 獣[けもの, けだもの]:beast/brute/animal, 獣[しし]:beast (esp. one used for its meat, such as a boar or a deer)|hunting (of animals such as boar, deer, etc.), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
それで
目は獲物を狙う獣みたいだった
（町）ひい〜
I can't picture anything but a bear.
熊[くま, クマ]:bear (any mammal of family Ursidae), 想像[そうぞう]:imagination/guess
熊しか想像できないんだけど
But it looks like I was wrong.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
でもね 違ったみたい
アハハハハ
うわあ:Wow!/Holy smokes!/Aaargh!, さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill
うわあ ごめん！
さっき… じゃなかった
Sorry, Sakki!
Wait, you aren't her.
I'm sorry.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person)
すみません
あっ さっきの亜人の…
It's that demi-human.
You're a foreigner?
外国[がいこく, そとぐに]:foreign country
（ひかり）外国の人？
（クルツ）あっ はい
Uh, yes.
We never see foreigners at this school!
学校[がっこう]:school, 外国人[がいこくじん]:foreigner/foreign citizen/foreign national, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 珍しい[めずらしい]:unusual|new|fine (e.g. gift), 金髪[きんぱつ, キンパツ]:blond hair
学校に外国人なんて珍しいね
金髪だし
You're even blond!
That's right. They're very uncommon here.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 珍しい[めずらしい]:unusual|new|fine (e.g. gift)
そうだね
すごく珍しいよね
So are we.
（雪）自分たちもね
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
（２人）アハハ
Oh, right!
そういえばそっか ハハッ
Huh? Your uniform's different, though.
制服[せいふく]:uniform
（ひかり）ん？　でも制服 違う
（クルツ）ぎくっ
Gulp!
Oh, I get it! You're transferring here?
転校生[てんこうせい]:transfer student/student changing schools
ああ そっか！　転校生？
そ… そっ そっ そうです
Th-Th-Th-That's right.
W-Well, bye!
そっ それじゃあ
Doesn't look like he's transferring here.
転校生[てんこうせい]:transfer student/student changing schools, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
転校生じゃないみたいだね
Really?
そうなの？
間違える[まちがえる]:to make a mistake (in)/to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)|to confuse
う〜ん なんで
サッキーと間違えたんだ 私？
Why did I mistake him for Sakki?
第[だい]:prefix for forming ordinal numbers, 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||
第一 男だし…
He's a boy, for one thing...
He was acting a little suspicious.
怪しい[あやしい]:suspicious/dubious|charming, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
ちょっと怪しい感じだったね
そうなの？
Was he?
That was too close.
危ない[あぶない]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain||, 危うい[あやうい]:dangerous|in danger|uncertain|, 怪しむ[あやしむ]:to suspect
（クルツ）
危ない 危ない
危うく 怪しまれるところだった
I think they almost started to suspect me.
Look at this!
（佐竹(さたけ)）見ろ これ
（クルツ）ん？
Th-This is...
（太田(おおた)）こっ これって…
（佐竹）な？
Right?
Sexy, right?
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent
（佐竹）エロいだろ？
（太田）うん
Yeah...
But, Satake, isn't this peeping?
盗撮[とうさつ]:sneak photography/non-consensual photography/peeping photos, じゃん:isn't it, 控えめ[ひかえめ]:moderate/reserved/conservative, 最低[さいてい]:least|worst|awful|
でも 佐竹 これ盗撮じゃん
控えめに言って最低だよ
Calling it a dirty trick is an understatement.
Shut up!
うるせえ
The picture is sexy enough,
写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 十分[じっぷん, じゅっぷん]:10 minutes, 十分[じゅうぶん]:plenty|division into ten|perfectly, エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, 実物[じつぶつ]:real thing/original/actual, 実物[みもの]:ornamental plant used primarily for the visual effect of its fruit, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
写真でも十分エロいけど
実物は もっとすごかったんだよ
but the real thing was even more intense!
Being hit by a succubus's... pheromones? I couldn't help it!
フェロモン:pheromone, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
サキュバスの
フェロモンみたいなのに
当てる[あてる]:to hit|to expose|to apply (e.g. patch)||
当てられちゃって
ついさ…
I kind of get how you feel, but...
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
気持ちは なんとなく分かるけど…
（２人）うわっ
（クルツ）け〜！
Don't look at Ms. Sakie with such lascivious eyes!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, なさる:to do
早紀絵先生を
やらしい目で見るのは やめなさい
Wha?
（太田）なっ
（佐竹）なんだ お前は！
Who are you?
I'm a passing pol—
通りすがり[とおりすがり]:passing by
僕は通りすがりのけ…
A passerby!
通りすがり[とおりすがり]:passing by
通りすがりの者だ
I meant specifically!
具体的[ぐたいてき]:concrete/tangible/definite
（佐竹）具体的に何だよ
You took this... in secret, didn't you?
こっそり:stealthily/secretly
これはこっそり… ん？
撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film), 卑劣[ひれつ]:mean/foul play/cowardly
撮ったものですね　卑劣な
How cowardly!
恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
こんなことをして 男として
恥ずかしくはないんですか？
As a man, aren't you ashamed to do things like this?
You heard him.
言われてますけど
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 汚い[きたない]:dirty|disordered|indecent (language, etc.)||
うう…
確かに汚いことをしたと思う
I do think what I did was pretty low.
But I'm a high school kid!
高校生[こうこうせい]:senior high school student, 健全[けんぜん]:healthy/sound/wholesome, 思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty
でも 俺も高校生なんだ
健全に思春期なんだ
I'm a healthy adolescent!
With a succubus like Satou as a teacher,
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
佐藤ちゃんみたいな
サキュバスの先生がいたら
it's weirder to tell me not to take interest!
興味を持つ[きょうみをもつ]:to have an interest, おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
興味を持つなというほうが
おかしい
Is it because she's a succubus?
（クルツ）
サキュバスだからですか？
（佐竹）あっ
Are you interested in Ms. Sakie because she's a succubus?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（クルツ）
早紀絵先生が
サキュバスだから
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for)
あなたは早紀絵先生に
興味があるのですか？
あ…
My taking that picture might have had something to do with that.
写真を撮る[しゃしんをとる]:to take a picture, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
つい写真を撮ってしまったことと
佐藤ちゃんが
サキュバスであることは
関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
関係あるかもしれない
But even if she weren't a succubus,
たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
しかし
サキュバスでなかったとしても
I still think Satou is cute!
佐藤ちゃんは
かわいいと思うし
I know that's kind of shady!
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
ちょっと やらしいなって思う〜！
（佐竹）ハア ハア…
（クルツ）フッ
Good answer.
答え[こたえ, いらえ]:answer/reply/response
（クルツ）いい答えです
Try not to forget that feeling.
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of
その気持ちを忘れないように
Just this once, I'll give you permission to keep that photo.
写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 特別[とくべつ]:special, 所有[しょゆう]:one's possessions/ownership, 許可[きょか]:permission/approval|to permit
その写真だけは
特別に所有を許可しましょう
ありゃ:oh/ah/I'll be darned, 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
何だ ありゃ
変なヤツだな
What was that about? He sure was weird.
I think you were pretty weird, too.
大概[たいがい]:in general|mainly|moderately
佐竹も大概だと思うよ
Anyway, where did Ugaki go?
それにしても宇垣さん
どこ行っちゃったんだ？
Smoking Room
フ〜
ハア〜 うま〜い
That's delicious...
（戸が開く音）
お？
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
こんにちは
Hello.
こんちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting)
こんちは
（戸が閉まる音）
Hello... Uh...
ああ… ええ…
Oh, my name is Takahashi.
ああ 高橋といいます
I'm Ugaki. Nice to meet you.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards
（宇垣）俺 宇垣　よろしく
Nice to meet you, Ugaki.
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
よろしくお願いします
宇垣さん
ほい
Here.
すみません
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
いいってことよ
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, たばこ:tobacco/cigarette|tobacco plant (Nicotiana tabacum), 吸う[すう]:to smoke|to suck|to absorb|
しかし 先生 たばこ吸うんだな
Anyway, so you smoke, huh?
Yes, occasionally.
たまに:occasionally/once in a while
ええ たまに
Occasionally, eh? How often is that?
たまに:occasionally/once in a while, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
たまにか どれくらい？
フウ〜
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
２年ぶりくらいですかね
I guess it's been about two years.
たまに:occasionally/once in a while, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
（宇垣）たまにすぎだろ
That's a little too occasional.
What made you suddenly decide to smoke today?
唐突[とうとつ]:abrupt/sudden, 吸う[すう]:to smoke|to suck|to absorb|
なんで 今日
唐突に吸おうと思ったんだ？
Is today special?
特別[とくべつ]:special
特別な日なの？
Huh? Me?
あっ 俺か
Yeah.
ええ
I heard your work involves demi-humans.
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
亜人関係の仕事をされていると
聞いたもので
誰が そんなことを？
Who told you that?
Was it Kurtz?
クルツか！
Yes, sort of.
ええ まあ
That idiot!
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal
あのバカ
まあ隠すことでもないしな
Well, it's nothing worth hiding, I guess.
Kurtz and I work for what's called the "Demi-human Division."
所属[しょぞく]:attached to/belong to/member, いわゆる:what is called/as it is called/the so-called, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 課[か]:lesson|section (in an organization)|counter for lessons and chapters (of a book), 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
俺とクルツの所属は
いわゆる亜人課って所だ
Oh! You're policemen from the Demi-human Division?
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 課[か]:lesson|section (in an organization)|counter for lessons and chapters (of a book), 刑事[けいじ]:(police) detective|criminal matter
おおっ 亜人課の刑事さん
I've never met one before!
初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
初めてお会いしました
Well, there aren't many demi-humans,
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 数[しばしば]:often/again and again/frequently, 数[かず]:number/amount, 少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce
（宇垣）まあな 亜人は数が少ない
which means incidents involving them are even rarer, right?
数[しばしば]:often/again and again/frequently, 数[かず]:number/amount, 少ない[すくない]:few/a little/scarce, 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
数が少なきゃ
事件はもっと少ない だろ？
Then, what kind of work do you do?
平時[へいじ]:normal times/peace time, どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
（高橋）
じゃあ 平時はどんな仕事を？
My work has nothing to do with demi-humans at all.
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||, 担当[たんとう]:being in charge (of an area of responsibility)/being responsible (for a work role, etc.)
亜人と全然関係ない
担当をしている
Huh?
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
（高橋）ええ〜
（宇垣）何 その顔
What kind of expression is that?
Though, back in the day, I was pretty busy...
昔[むかし]:olden days/former, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless
（宇垣）
でも まあ
昔はもっと忙しかったな
昔[むかし]:olden days/former, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 対する[たいする]:to face (each other)|to be directed toward (the future, etc.)|to receive (a client, etc.)||, とげとげ:sharply/harshly/stingingly, 世の中[よのなか]:society/the world/the times
昔は今より亜人に対して
とげとげしててな 世の中が
The world used to be a lot harsher toward demi-humans.
Since they had it rough both socially and psychologically,
生活[せいかつ]:living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, 精神的[せいしんてき]:mental/emotional, 苦しい[くるしい]:painful|needy|forced (smile, joke)||, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person)
生活的にも精神的にも苦しい
亜人が
we'd often see demi-humans causing problems.
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||, 起こす[おこす]:to raise|to wake|to cause||, ちょいちょい:often/frequently/now and then
問題を起こすということが
ちょいちょいあった
最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now
でも 最近は
そういうこと まず聞かねえ
But lately, you never hear of that happening.
Because the government took action?
国[くに]:country|region|national government||, 手を打つ[てをうつ]:to take measures (in face of events being anticipated)|to come to an agreement (in bargaining, etc.)|to clap one's hands together, 保障[ほしょう]:guarantee/security/assurance, 制度[せいど]:system/institution/organization
（高橋）
国が手を打ったから？
保障制度とか
The guarantee system?
（宇垣）それもあるだろうが
That's probably part of it,
but as a whole, society sort of mellowed out.
わりと:relatively/comparatively, 自然[しぜん]:nature|natural|naturally, 世の中[よのなか]:society/the world/the times, 丸い[まるい, まろい]:round/circular|harmonious
わりと自然と
世の中が丸くなったというか
I realized that again today.
実感[じっかん]:real feeling/actual feeling|to actually feel
今日も それを実感したよ
Today?
（高橋）今日？
This school has three demi-human students, right?
学校[がっこう]:school, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person)
（宇垣）
この学校
亜人の子 ３人もいるだろ？
I haven't heard any bad rumors,
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
悪いウワサは聞かなかったが
but a part of me was scared to look into it.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 確認[かくにん]:confirmation/verification/validation, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, 節[せつ]:occasion|section (of a literary work)|principle||, 節[のっと, ノット]:knot (nautical mile per hour)
やっぱり ちょっと確認するのが
怖い節があった
実際[じっさい]:practicality|reality|bhutakoti (limit of reality), 開ける[あける]:to open (a door, etc.)|to open (for business, etc.)|to empty||, 開ける[ひらける]:to become opened up|to develop|to be enlightened, びっくり:to be surprised/to be amazed|surprise (e.g. surprise party), 玉手箱[たまてばこ]:treasure chest (in the story of Urashima Taro)/Urashima's casket|important secret that is not easily revealed to others
でも 実際 見てみたら
開けてびっくり玉手箱
But once I actually did, I was surprised by what I found.
They look like they're having a great time.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
みんな すごく楽しそうにしてる
It almost made me want to cry.
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob
おじさん
少し泣きそうになったよ
I started to think the world's heading in a good direction.
世の中[よのなか]:society/the world/the times, 方向[ほうこう]:direction/orientation|course (e.g. of action), 向かう[むかう]:to face|to go towards/to head towards
世の中 いい方向に
向かっているんだろうなって
I'm sure how they were raised is part of it,
親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.), 御[ご]:honorific/polite|honorific suffix, 御[ぎょ]:honorific affix|honorific prefix, 教育[きょういく]:training/education
親御さんの教育も
そうだろうし
and they're probably blessed with good teachers, too.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 恵まれる[めぐまれる]:to be blessed with/to be rich in/to abound in
先生にも恵まれてるのかな
Sorry I took your Demi-human Division job.
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 課[か]:lesson|section (in an organization)|counter for lessons and chapters (of a book), 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 取る[とる]:to take|to steal|to eat||, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
亜人課のお仕事を取ってしまって
すみません
言いよる[いいよる]:to court/to woo/to approach defiantly
ハッ 言いよる
Bold words!
フウ〜
But unfortunately, I have a job that you can never take from me.
残念[ざんねん]:deplorable/bad luck/regret, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 奪う[うばう]:to snatch away/to dispossess/to steal, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
だが 残念なことに
先生には絶対 奪えない仕事がある
ん？　というと？
Meaning?
The majority of incidents caused by demi-humans
現在[げんざい]:now/current/present, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 関わる[かかわる]:to be affected|to be concerned with|to stick to (opinions), 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident, 大多数[だいたすう]:great majority, 占める[しめる]:to occupy/to hold|to account for
（宇垣）
現在 亜人が関わる事件の
大多数を占めるもの
are incidents involving aphrodisiac effects.
淫魔[いんま]:incubus/succubus/demon appearing in a dream, 関わる[かかわる]:to be affected|to be concerned with|to stick to (opinions), 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident
淫魔(いんま)が関わる催淫事件だ
Aphrodisiac effects?
事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident
催淫事件
You mean incidents caused by succubi's aphrodisiac effects, right?
起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents), 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
サキュバスの催淫によって
起きる事件みたいなことですよね？
Let's say a succubus is molested.
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 痴漢[ちかん]:masher/molester/pervert, 遭う[あう]:to meet/to encounter|to have an accident, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
（宇垣）
例えば サキュバスが
痴漢に遭ったとする
意図[いと]:intention/aim/design, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
意図せず催淫してしまって
It isn't always true that the succubus used her aphrodisiac effect accidentally.
痴漢[ちかん]:masher/molester/pervert, 遭う[あう]:to meet/to encounter|to have an accident, パターン:pattern
痴漢に遭うって
パターンだけじゃなく
Some of them intentionally use it to get molested.
意図的[いとてき]:intentional/on purpose, 痴漢[ちかん]:masher/molester/pervert, 場合[ばあい]:case/situation
意図的に催淫して
痴漢させるって場合もあるんだ
Serves you right!
Determining whether the succubus used the aphrodisiac effect
側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case, 意思[いし]:intention/wish/purpose
サキュバス側に
催淫する意思はあったのか
deliberately is extremely difficult.
事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident, 判断[はんだん]:judgment|divination|judgement, 非常[ひじょう]:emergency|extraordinary/unusual, 難しい[むずかしい, むつかしい]:difficult|fussy|gloomy||
催淫事件は
この判断が非常に難しい
What teacher could actually steal that job?
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 一介[いっかい]:mere/only a ..., 教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom), 奪う[うばう]:to snatch away/to dispossess/to steal
この仕事
一介の教師に奪えるかね？
W-Wait a second.
くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
（高橋）
ちょっ ちょっと待ってください
Huh?
（宇垣）ん？
（高橋）それって
You mean there's a way to make the correct judgment in those cases?
正しい[ただしい]:right/correct|proper, 判断[はんだん]:judgment|divination|judgement, 下す[くだす]:to make a decision|to give a judgement|to let go down||, 下す[おろす]:to take down (e.g. flag)|to drop off (a passenger from a vehicle)|to withdraw money from an account||, 方法[ほうほう]:method/process/manner
正しい判断を下す方法は
あるんですか？
There's no failsafe method.
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 方法[ほうほう]:method/process/manner
こうすれば絶対という方法はない
All we can do right now
今の俺たちができることは
is to maintain communication with succubi in our jurisdictions,
管轄[かんかつ]:jurisdiction/control, 内[うち]:inside|while|among||, 内[ない]:inside/within
管轄内のサキュバスと
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, コミュニケーションをとる:to communicate
少しでも
コミュニケーションをとって
and determine in advance if they're malicious or not.
悪意[あくい]:ill will|bad meaning|mala fides|, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 人物[じんぶつ]:person|one's character|able person
そういう悪意を持つ人物かどうか
あらかじめ:beforehand/in advance/previously, 人となり[ひととなり]:hereditary disposition/temperament|body build, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
あらかじめ人となりを
知っておくことくらいなもんだ
I bet succubi don't like you much, huh?
嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe
サキュバスからは
嫌われそうですね
I'm basically interrogating them about things that may or may not happen.
起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, 事件[じけん]:event/affair/incident
起こるかも分からん事件の
取り調べ[とりしらべ]:investigation (e.g. by police or prosecutors)/examination/inquiry
取り調べを
してるようなものだからな
All I can tell them is that it's my job.
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 割り切る[わりきる]:to find a clear solution/to come to a clean decision|to divide
それを仕事だと割り切るしかない
It isn't like I want them to hate me.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe
ホントは嫌われたくないけど
So you haven't reached any compromise?
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, 折り合う[おりあう]:to compromise
全然 折り合いついてないですね
フ〜
Well, I do occasionally meet succubi I get along with, for whatever reason.
まっ たま〜に
合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
なぜかウマが合う
サキュバスがいたりするが
There's one rather unusual one...
変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
ちょっと変わったヤツが…
By the way, I hear you're pretty knowledgeable about demis.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
ところで 先生は
詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
デミのことに
詳しいみたいだな
Oh, not really...
いやあ そんなには
But you do know about the nickname "demis."
呼び方[よびかた]:way of calling
（宇垣）
デミって呼び方は
知ってるんだな
（高橋）え？
（宇垣）フン
Mr. Takahashi, take care of Sakie, will ya?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, よろしく:well/properly|best regards
先生 早紀絵をよろしくな
ほかのデミちゃんたちは？
What about the other demis?
フッフフ そうだな
Right.
Take care of all the demis, including Sakie,
始め[はじめ]:beginning|first (in line, etc.)|origin|, よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
早紀絵を始め
デミちゃんたちをよろしくな 先生
Mr. Takahashi...
ん！
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer
俺はもっと
I'll do my best to make this a world where demis can feel at ease.
安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice, 世の中[よのなか]:society/the world/the times, 頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
デミが安心できる世の中になるよう
頑張るからよ
You just do your best to look after each of them.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 一人一人[ひとりひとり, ひとりびとり]:one by one/each/one at a time, しっかり:tightly (holding on)/firmly|strongly (built)
先生は 一人一人のデミを
しっかり見てやってくれよ
Give them lots of good memories.
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 思い出[おもいで]:memories/recollections/reminiscence, たくさん:a lot/lots|enough, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
楽しい思い出
たくさん作ってやってくれな
Okay... You can count on me.
任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
はい 任せてください
ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter)
ハハハ…
笑い声[わらいごえ]:laughter
（２人の笑い声）
When you interact with demis, is there anything you're careful about?
接する[せっする]:to touch|to receive (e.g. visitor)|to receive (news)||
（高橋）
宇垣さんは
デミの子と接するとき
気をつける[きをつける]:to be careful/to pay attention/to take care
気をつけていることとか
ありますか？
Rather than try to make them like me, I try to make them not hate me.
好く[すく]:to like/to love/to be fond of, 好く[よく]:nicely/properly|frequently, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe
（宇垣）
好かれようとするよりも
嫌われないようにするってことかな
Smoking Room
If being hated by girls is "100,"
女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe, 個[こ, コ]:counter for articles|counter for military units|individual, 個[か, カ]:counter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted)/a noun read using its on-yomi
女の子が嫌うことが100個
and being hated by demis is "100,"
嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe, 個[こ, コ]:counter for articles|counter for military units|individual, 個[か, カ]:counter for the ichi-ni-san counting system (usu. directly preceding the item being counted)/a noun read using its on-yomi
デミが嫌うことが
100個あるとすれば
then being hated by demi girls would be 100 x 100, which is 10,000.
女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe, 掛ける[かける]:to hang (e.g. picture)|to sit|to take (time, money)||, 万[ばん]:many/all, 万[まん, よろず]:10,000|myriad|everything|
デミの女の子が嫌うことは
100掛ける100で１万
You can really express it with such simple math?
単純[たんじゅん]:simplicity/simple/uncomplicated, 計算[けいさん]:calculation/reckoning|forecast
（高橋）
そんなに単純な計算で
いいんですか？
It's only an example.
例え話[たとえばなし]:allegory/fable/parable, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 複雑[ふくざつ]:complex/complicated/mixed (feelings)
例え話だよ
それくらい複雑ってこと
That's just how complicated it is.
You might find yourself distanced from them for surprising reasons, too.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 意外[いがい]:unexpected/surprising, 距離を開く[きょりをひらく]:to open the distance
先生も意外なことで
距離を開けられるかもな
Please don't try to scare me.
脅かす[おどかす]:to threaten/to menace|to startle, 脅かす[おびやかす]:to intimidate/to scare|to jeopardize, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
脅かさないでください
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひかり）先生！
Mr. T!
おっ ウワサをすれば
Speak of the devil.
Are you done talking now?
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
お話 終わったの？
Yeah, I guess.
ああ まあな
Hi there, little lady vampire.
こんにちは:hello/good day (daytime greeting), バンパイア:vampire, お嬢[おじょう]:(someone else's) daughter
こんにちは
バンパイアのお嬢ちゃん
My name's Ugaki.
俺 宇垣っていうんだ
I'm Takanashi Hikari, from class 1-B!
組[くみ]:set (of items)|group (of people)|typesetting, ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
１年Ｂ組の小鳥遊(たかなし)ひかりです
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you!
"Little lady," he said!
お嬢[おじょう]:(someone else's) daughter
お嬢ちゃんですって エヘヘ
Yeah, good for you.
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
アハハ よかったね
（ひかり）ん？
（高橋）ん？
Huh?
Sniff, sniff. Sniff, sniff.
（嗅ぐ音）
（高橋）おお 何だ？
Uh, what?
You stink!
臭い[くさい]:stinking|suspicious|clumsy||, 臭い[におい]:odour/odor|aura
（ひかり）臭い
（２人）ああ…
たばこ:tobacco/cigarette|tobacco plant (Nicotiana tabacum), 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
（ひかり）ハハッ たばこ嫌〜い
（高橋）あっ
I hate cigarettes!
I guess she's sensitive to cigarette smoke.
煙たい[けむたい, けぶたい]:smoky|awkward/ill at ease, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
（高橋）煙たがられてしまいました
（宇垣）ハッ
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 課[か]:lesson|section (in an organization)|counter for lessons and chapters (of a book), っつう:meaning/called/said, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
（宇垣）
とまあ 亜人課っつうのは
こんな感じでだな
So, anyway, that's how I deal with demi-humans.
Occasionally, I go out to meet
demi-humans out of my jurisdiction.
たまに:occasionally/once in a while, 管轄[かんかつ]:jurisdiction/control, 内[うち]:inside|while|among||, 内[ない]:inside/within, 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person)
たまに管轄内の亜人に
会いに行ったりするわけだ
まあ あのデミちゃんたちは
But I don't think the police will have to do anything about those demis.
警察[けいさつ]:police|police officer|police station, どうこう:trend/tendency/movement, どうこう:similar tastes, 必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
警察が どうこうする必要は
ないだろう
It's just that succubus.
やはり:too/also|still
やはり サキュバスだな
いずれ:where/which|anyway, 本腰を入れる[ほんごしをいれる]:to set about in earnest/to put one's back into something, 働く[はたらく]:to work|to function|to commit (e.g. a crime)|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
いずれ お前にも本腰を入れて
働いてもらうことになるだろ…
Someday, I'll probably need to have you do some serious work for us...
たこ焼き[たこやき, タコやき]:octopus dumplings, うまる:to be buried/to be covered|to overflow
ん〜 たこ焼き うまっ
Takoyaki is so good!
I'll smack him later...
引っぱたく[ひっぱたく]:to slap/to strike/to spank
（宇垣）あとで引っぱたこう
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
〜♪
Demis Want to Learn
Next Time
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate
（ひまり）
次回「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
Demis Want to Learn.
亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 学ぶ[まなぶ]:to study (in depth)/to learn/to take lessons in
「亜人ちゃんは
学びたい」